<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-17T23:57:27+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Halim Awalurahman</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">My New Blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/01/16/my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My New Blog" /><published>2024-01-16T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/01/16/my-new-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/01/16/my-new-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;For awhile, I have doubts and concerns about my blog. I have used various blog platform such as Blogger, Wordpres, and Medium. Recently, I want something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress was probably the one that lasted longest to me. They have social-media like system, in which I have made some acquintances over time. Blogger was perhaps the simplest. It’s basically just a content management system where I write my posts and not worry over the views, followers, and all that stuff. Medium was the one I used recently. It’s great, it’s minimalistic, it’s easy. However, one thing that I don’t really like from these blogging platform is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I don’t have the ownership of my content – in other words – I hate seeing my content displaying ads. Which most of the times does not have any relevance to my content. I also think that if I want to share something, at this point, I should make it available to as many people as possible - not limited by paywall or annoying ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started looking for options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first initial idea was just to have plain html site with Bootstrap. I did develop this idea. It looks great and it seems to be working, at first. Then I ran to this issue: it would be very hard to write posts with this idea. I would have to create multiple html pages with different codes, since I use plain ones. Further issue that I thought of was that even if I could use front-end frameworks to help me manage the content, I would have to deal with the deployment process - which can be very confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I trace back what I really want my blog to be. I want to select the best platform that best fit my use case. Here are my use case (as of now):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to showcase my works and publications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to be able to write things (posts)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I hate ads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want easy deployment - possibly free ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across few solutions that might fit with those. The solutions include Jekyll, Hugo, and Substack. I am not going to explain each of them, you can always find them online. I will, though, say something about Substack. I found substack in Twitter and YouTube. It’s basically just like Medium, except that it does not require your readers to pay anything. It does not contain any ads either. As far as I know, it looks like a perfect solution. I have even made an account in it. However, somehow, I don’t feel like using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am more interested in one solution that requires some learning curve - Jekyll. So I used it in building this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I have learned Ubuntu, Ruby (though very minimal), Gem, and Jekyll itself. I used Ubuntu in Windows so it’s a bit weird. To be honest, I have never used it for a long time. I think the last time I touched Ubuntu was when I had to use it in Operating System class. But I have to say that it is nice to learn and actually feel that I accomplish something. Each day I figured something new and recalled what I have learned in the past. It’s been fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this is my story. Will I ever stick to Jekyll? probably. I think it’s time to settle in one thing and be consistent. Will I ever find something that I don’t like in Jekyll? most likely. I am easily bored. I may complain about somethings – and by the way, I have a complain about Jekyll front matter already but lets keep it for another time hahahaha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to share more things here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For awhile, I have doubts and concerns about my blog. I have used various blog platform such as Blogger, Wordpres, and Medium. Recently, I want something new.</summary></entry></feed>