<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://hawalurahman.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://hawalurahman.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-06-17T23:26:43+07:00</updated><id>https://hawalurahman.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Halim Awalurahman</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Declutter</title><link href="https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/06/17/declutter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Declutter" /><published>2024-06-17T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/06/17/declutter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/06/17/declutter.html">&lt;p&gt;When the workload seems to be hard and burdening, the first thing I do is investigate whether I have a cluttered desk or not. Having been decluttering for a long time, it became intuitive to clean my desk. Along the cleaning process, I find it relaxing and help me calm down. Removing junks and reorganize cables feels like removing the cloud inside my head. Often I found resolution and ideas on what to do next while I clean my desk. I know nothing about psychology or behavioral science, but decluttering helps me alot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Uncluttered desk leads to uncluttered mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2019, I have been a fan of minimalism and decluttering, especially for work desk. The idea is to have only what we really need during the work. For me, my laptop, a keyboard, a mouse, and a monitor is enough to have in my desk. I rarely used pen or pencil but I do have like a cup holder for them in my desk too. The key is to have only what I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this idea to my college dormitory up until now. Wherever I have a work desk, the only things you will see are mentioned above, with some exceptions if I have limited surface appliances. But the idea is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once in a while, usually in about 2-3 weeks, I like to evaluate how my desk looks and feel. If it began to feel cramped or crowded with useless stuff, I sort them up and re-organize it to make it work again. Let’s call this activity as decluttering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My simple approach to decluttering is to &lt;strong&gt;throw away things that are not useful&lt;/strong&gt; anymore and &lt;strong&gt;keep the other in the drawer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I threw away things such as plastic from things or packages that I unwrap on my desk or other small things like a pen cap or empty pen or broken stuff. For the stuff that I keep in my drawer, usually consist of books I have (or haven’t - and not really urgent) read, notebooks, papers (which mostly filled with sketches and idea dumps), office supplies, phone chargers, and electronics (earphone, watch, external hard drives, flash disk, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, since I had to throw things into my drawer too, I had to evaluate what is in there that I may want to dispose. Old batteries for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I have sorted everything and the remaining things on my desk are what I actually need, I will clean the surface. Wet tissue often do the tricks. I then wipe it again with paper towel to help it dry faster. I like to see a shiny desk (and actually feel it too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also special approach if I have monitor or many electronic devices that I have to keep around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if usually I declutter once every 2-3 weeks, I have a more strict rules regarding to electronics especially cables. I hate cables laying around on my desk. I have switched my mouse and keyboard to the wireless ones to avoid the mess of having cables laying around. However for audio devices I still have some compromises as the wireless audio device often lacks clear microphone so I stick with wired ones.  So basically, I hate cables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For electronics and cables, once every 3-5 days I will begin to feel uncomfortable and organize them in a way that does not hamper my productivity and easy on the eye. One simple trick I use is to have a tiny gap between my desk and the wall, and throw every cable there to hide the mess. This is especially helpful for stationary devices such as laptop. I kept the charger brick (since I have a gaming laptop) on the desk but throw the cables down the gap so they become less visible. As for phone or other devices chargers, I bought a cable tie with velcro to help reorganize them. I roll them up and tie them, then throw them into my drawer. When I need to charge, I can easily retrieve the roll from the drawer. This approach has helped me in keeping my desk simple and uncluttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Declutter has been an important part of my productivity routine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to have a clean desk. It helps me to focus on things that are actually important. It removes distraction and unnecessary interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declutter your desk and feel the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Halim&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When the workload seems to be hard and burdening, the first thing I do is investigate whether I have a cluttered desk or not. Having been decluttering for a long time, it became intuitive to clean my desk. Along the cleaning process, I find it relaxing and help me calm down. Removing junks and reorganize cables feels like removing the cloud inside my head. Often I found resolution and ideas on what to do next while I clean my desk. I know nothing about psychology or behavioral science, but decluttering helps me alot.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Connecting Jekyll to Obsidian</title><link href="https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/04/18/connecting-jekyll-to-obsidian.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Connecting Jekyll to Obsidian" /><published>2024-04-18T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/04/18/connecting-jekyll-to-obsidian</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/04/18/connecting-jekyll-to-obsidian.html">&lt;p&gt;This post is created using Obsidian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My workaround is following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;clone my github repository to my local computer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pull everything&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; folder inside Jekyll as an Obsidian Vault&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write the thing that you want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;save&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out to be quite easy - I don’t have to pull out &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wsl2&lt;/code&gt; for this anymore. It is simpler but does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it does.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This post is created using Obsidian.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting off the grid</title><link href="https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/01/18/getting-off-the-grid.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting off the grid" /><published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-01-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/01/18/getting-off-the-grid</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/01/18/getting-off-the-grid.html">&lt;p&gt;I recently found a series compilation on YouTube. The series was called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parks_and_Recreation&quot;&gt;Parks and Recreation&lt;/a&gt;. I found one character really funny and relatable, Ron Swanson. In this particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GDDof2NHInA&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;, Ron wanted to go ‘off the grid’, completely isolating himself from the internet. I recently thought about that video, specifically about the idea of going off the grid. Here is my take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time when I enjoyed social media a lot. Today? not so much. When I look at it, I think the biggest factor of my enjoyment was interaction with my friends. I used to share a lot of stories, memes, and random stuff, and I would get funny comments and reactions from them. It was enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t do as much of those things recently. I realized that I did not put enough effort into maintaining the interaction and the fun just seemed to fade away. It is probably my fault too. There were times when I isolated myself from the world – and in one way or another, I made some distance both physically and virtually with my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But getting off the grid for me was not exactly about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put things simply, I will say that I get overwhelmed by the amount of information streaming through my screens. I got up every morning and the first thing I checked was social media, mostly Twitter (yes, I still call it that instead of X). I would scroll around and sucked into the tiny little world, diving into streams of information and recent trends, until eventually, I lost track of time. Another case was when I used my computer for work. Often times, I found that when I am losing my focus or bored, I just CTRL+T and type ‘twit..’ and Twitter instantly popped up. I scroll away again, abandoning my tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think, social media made me think that I am part of something – part of a community that discusses things that I might be interested in. Being part of something often times made me lose track of where I am, or where I should be. I should’ve been working but instead, I found random dudes arguing online about which one is best: Ronaldo or Messi very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I found something that made me hate Twitter. It’s January 2024 and we’re close to the general election here in Indonesia. Guess what? Hundreds of Buzzers flooded my timeline and I hate it. My timeline is now mostly politics. Often times I found random tweets insulting and inappropriate. Oh, and dozens of ads floating around Twitter – often about judi and inappropriate stuff, I hate it. I feel like my timeline is not as fun anymore. Not much Real Madrid news and things that I used to enjoy anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the things mentioned above, I logged out of Twitter on my desktop and removed Twitter from my homescreen on my phone. Often I hear that to stay away from distraction, we have to keep our distance from the source. I still occasionally check it, but only in my following tabs to see Extra Time Indonesia making fun of football clubs and matches. Oh, and I muted and reported a lot of accounts – just because I hate them and I want them to burn to the ground (wow I am so evil).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now enjoying my time ‘semi’ off the grid. I save time and can actually focus on myself. I just started staying away from Twitter this week, and I achieved quite a lot of things. More importantly, I get to work on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess, what I want to say is, sometimes you can get uncomfortable in an environment so that you consider leaving. If you do choose to leave, you will have more time to work on yourself and things that are important to you. Additionally, the streams of information today can be overwhelming and it is our job to filter which one is important and which one is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not realize how lost I was in the stream. Now, I regulate myself and use the streams with a lot of consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side, I still want to see updates and interact with my friends. In fact, I just hope it’s just me and my friends – no ads, no buzzer – just things that I hold close and important to me. So, until then, I guess I will be staying out of the streams. I want to discover something else that will give me fulfilment and enjoyment. Something that is worth to spend my time on. Something that actually matters to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I will enjoy fishing or hunting (nah I don’t have the facility hahahah). Oh, I spent a lot of times with my family too – being more present, talking to my cats, greeting the parking man when we go out, joke around while driving my mom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh wow, there’s just so much more than just staring at people making threads. Including writing one of my own. With longer characters. No ads. That does not have to have ‘click-bait’ or ‘showboating’. This blog is now my runaway – perhaps could be yours too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halim&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I recently found a series compilation on YouTube. The series was called Parks and Recreation. I found one character really funny and relatable, Ron Swanson. In this particular video, Ron wanted to go ‘off the grid’, completely isolating himself from the internet. I recently thought about that video, specifically about the idea of going off the grid. Here is my take.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My New Blog</title><link href="https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/01/16/my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My New Blog" /><published>2024-01-16T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/01/16/my-new-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hawalurahman.github.io/2024/01/16/my-new-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;For awhile, I have doubts and concerns about my blog. I have used various blog platform such as Blogger, Wordpres, and Medium. Recently, I want something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress was probably the one that lasted longest to me. They have social-media like system, in which I have made some acquintances over time. Blogger was perhaps the simplest. It’s basically just a content management system where I write my posts and not worry over the views, followers, and all that stuff. Medium was the one I used recently. It’s great, it’s minimalistic, it’s easy. However, one thing that I don’t really like from these blogging platform is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I don’t have the ownership of my content – in other words – I hate seeing my content displaying ads. Which most of the times does not have any relevance to my content. I also think that if I want to share something, at this point, I should make it available to as many people as possible - not limited by paywall or annoying ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started looking for options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first initial idea was just to have plain html site with Bootstrap. I did develop this idea. It looks great and it seems to be working, at first. Then I ran to this issue: it would be very hard to write posts with this idea. I would have to create multiple html pages with different codes, since I use plain ones. Further issue that I thought of was that even if I could use front-end frameworks to help me manage the content, I would have to deal with the deployment process - which can be very confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I trace back what I really want my blog to be. I want to select the best platform that best fit my use case. Here are my use case (as of now):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to showcase my works and publications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to be able to write things (posts)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I hate ads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want easy deployment - possibly free ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across few solutions that might fit with those. The solutions include Jekyll, Hugo, and Substack. I am not going to explain each of them, you can always find them online. I will, though, say something about Substack. I found substack in Twitter and YouTube. It’s basically just like Medium, except that it does not require your readers to pay anything. It does not contain any ads either. As far as I know, it looks like a perfect solution. I have even made an account in it. However, somehow, I don’t feel like using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am more interested in one solution that requires some learning curve - Jekyll. So I used it in building this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I have learned Ubuntu, Ruby (though very minimal), Gem, and Jekyll itself. I used Ubuntu in Windows so it’s a bit weird. To be honest, I have never used it for a long time. I think the last time I touched Ubuntu was when I had to use it in Operating System class. But I have to say that it is nice to learn and actually feel that I accomplish something. Each day I figured something new and recalled what I have learned in the past. It’s been fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this is my story. Will I ever stick to Jekyll? probably. I think it’s time to settle in one thing and be consistent. Will I ever find something that I don’t like in Jekyll? most likely. I am easily bored. I may complain about somethings – and by the way, I have a complain about Jekyll front matter already but lets keep it for another time hahahaha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to share more things here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For awhile, I have doubts and concerns about my blog. I have used various blog platform such as Blogger, Wordpres, and Medium. Recently, I want something new.</summary></entry></feed>